A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Conan's logic works wonders on hearts exhausted by modern society!
تُعالج استنتاجات كونان القلوب المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today's hints are crabs and a whale! Unexpected things look like them!
!تلميح اليوم سرطانات وحوت! أشياء غير متوقعة تبدو مثلها
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The Crabs and Whale Kidnapping Case
قضيّة اختطاف السرطانات والحوت
Cheers!
!نخبكم
Tastes great! Can't have summer without beer!
!لذيذ! لا غنى عن الجعّة في الصيف
Dad! You shouldn't just drink! You need to eat a little!
.أبي، لا يجدر بك الاكتفاء بالشرب عليك الأكل قليلاً
Yeah, yeah. Don't be so naggy.
أجل، أفهم. لا تنقِّي
I was all excited when he said it was a fancy hotel dinner,
أتيتُ متحمساً بعدما قال أنّنا سنتعشّى في فندق فاخر
but it's nothing but light snacks!
لكنّها ليست سوى مجرّد أكلات جانبيّة مع شراب
Who takes kids to beer gardens to eat?
من يصطحب أطفالاً لحدائق جعّة للأكل؟
Dentist - Endo Keigo (33)
(إيندو كيغو (33 طبيب أسنان
That man's at a beer garden but hasn't even had a sip...
هذا الرجل في حديقة جعّة، لكنه لم يشرب ولا قطرة
Are you drunk already?!
هل ثملت من الآن يا أبي؟
No...
...كلا
Where are you going?
أين تذهب؟
Bathroom.
دورة المياه
The bathrooms aren't that way! Really, now...
...ليست من ذاك الاتّجاه! لا أمل منك حقّاً
This way!
!تعال
Alright...
...أجل
This is Endo...
أجل، معك إيندو
Yes. Yes. I'm alone.
أجل، أجل. أنا بمفردي
What?!
!ماذا؟
Why is the deal off?! I got the money and didn't tell the police!
لمَ أُلغيت الصفقة؟ جهّزتُ المال !ولم أخبر الشرطة
Wait! Let me hear Keita again! Hello?!
!انتظر! دعني أسمع صوت كيتا مُجدداً مرحباً؟ مرحباً؟
Did this man--
...أيمكن أنّ هذا الشخص
Old man! Ran-neechan!
!عمّ! ران-نيتشان
Let's get out of here!
!لنخرج من هنا سريعاً
What's the matter, Conan-kun?
ما الخطب يا كونان-كن؟
I can't say it out loud, but I think there was a kidnapping!
لا يمكنني رفع صوتي، لكن أظنّ أن اختطافاً وقع
What?!
!ماذا؟
Just as you said, there's a good chance they're holding him for ransom.
كما قلت، هناك احتمال عالٍ باختطافهم ابنه وطلب فدية مالية مقابله
Yeah. It sounds like he hasn't contacted the police.
أجل، يبدو أنّه لم يخبر الشرطة
Driver. Try not to lose the taxi in front of us.
حضرة السائق، احرص على ألّا تفقد سيّارة الأجرة أمامنا
Right.
حاضر
Endo Dental Clinic
عيادة إيندو الطبيّة للأسنان
Closed for today.
مُغلق
A dentist, huh...
طبيب أسنان إذاً؟
What now, Dad?
ماذا سنفعل الآن يا أبي؟
We need to talk with him first...
...علينا اللقاء به والكلام معه أوّلاً
But we don't know where the kidnapper is looking from,
لكن لا نعرف من أين يراقب الخاطف
and it could be a neighbor behind this.
وقد يكون أحد الجيران
We'll need to be careful.
علينا توخّي الحذر
I have a good idea! I'll be a patient!
!لديّ فكرة جيّدة! سأكون مريضاً
Patient?
مريض؟
Alright, start.
حسناً، ابدأ
My tooth hurts! It hurts!
!ضرسي يؤلمني! أونيتشان
Hold on! Dad's going to talk to the dentist!
!مؤلم! مؤلم! مؤلم
No, I can't hold on! It hurts!
!لا، لا أستطيع الصبر! مؤلم
Yes?
نعم؟
I'm sorry to bother you on your day off.
أعتذر على مقاطعة راحتك
My kid's tooth hurts and he won't shut up about it.
لديّ صغير هنا تؤلمه أسنانه ولا يستطيع التحمّل
Could you look at it?
هلّا ألقيت نظرةً عليه؟
I can't stand it!
!مؤلم! لا أستطيع الاحتمال
Understood. Please come inside.
حسناً... تفضّلوا بالدخول
It hurts! It hurts!
!مؤلم! مؤلم
Please come in.
ادخلوا
I apologize...
المعذرة
Ouch--
!مؤلم
Ouch!
!آخ
Knock it off! That's enough!
!يكفي! إلى متى ستواصل هذا؟
Please come into the examination room...
تـ-توجّهوا لغرفة الفحص من فضلكم
Mori Kogoro? That famous detective?!
موري كوغورو؟ ذاك المتحرّي الشهير؟
I see. So Conan-kun heard my phone conversation--
فهمت، سمع كونان-كن مكالمتي إذاً
Endo-san. Could you tell me about it?
إيندو-سان، هلّا أخبرتنا بالموضوع؟
If the kid's right, then I can help you.
إن ما قاله الولد صحيحاً، فيمكنني مساعدتك
Alright. This may be some sort of fate.
حسناً، قد يكون هذا القدر
Just as you said, my son was kidnapped.
كما قلتم، اُختطف ابني
His name is Keita.
اسمه كيتا
I let him play by himself in the front yard this afternoon, but...
تركته يلعب بمفرده في الفناء ...الأمامي ظهيرة اليوم، لكن
Keita! Let's go to the park!
كيتا، ما رأيك أن نذهب للحديقة؟
Keita?
كيتا؟
"Took the kid. Call the police and he's dead. Wait for a call."
"أخذتُ الصبيّ، إذا اتّصلت بالشرطة سأقتله. انتظر اتّصالي"
It's written on ordinary copy paper.
إنّها مكتوبة على ورقة طباعة عادية
So what did the kidnapper tell you?
بما أخبرك الخاطف إذاً؟
It was a young man's voice on the phone.
كان صوت رجل شاب على الهاتف
He told me to put 30 million yen in used bills in a briefcase
أخبرني بوضع 30 مليون ين بعملات قديمة في حقيبة
and to be at Starlight Hotel's beer garden at 6:00.
والتواجد في حديقة الجعّة لفندق ستارلايت عند السادسة
But a little after 6:00, he called me and cancelled the exchange.
لكن بعد السادسة بقليل، اتّصل بي وأنا أنتظر وألغى الصفقة فجأةً
Did he explain why?
أوضّح السبب؟
No. All he said was that he would call again tomorrow morning.
كلا، كلّ ما قاله أنّه سيعاود الاتّصال صباح الغد
Maybe the kidnapper was suspicious?
لعلّ حادثاً ما اعترضه
He probably never intended to get the money tonight.
لم ينو أخذ المال الليلة من البداية غالباً
He likely watched Endo-san from somewhere in the beer garden
كان يشاهد إيندو-سان من مكان ما في حديقة الجعّة
to make sure he hadn't contacted the police.
ليتأكد من أنّه لم يتّصل بالشرطة على الأرجح
When you got the first call, did you hear Keita-kun's voice?
،عندما تلقّيت الاتّصال الأوّل أسمعت صوت كيتا-كن؟
Yes. I asked the kidnapper to put him on the phone.
أجل، طلبتُ من الخاطف إعطاءه الهاتف
How did Keita-kun seem?
كيف بدا كيتا-كن؟
He sounded unexpectedly cheerful; he didn't seem afraid at all.
كان مُبتهجاً لحدّ مُفاجئ، ولم يبد خائفاً البتّة
That is odd. You would expect him to at least miss his mother.
هذا غريب، تتوقّع أن يفتقد أمّه في العادة
He doesn't have one.
لا أمّ لديه
She died of a disease last year.
توفّيت بمرض في العام الفائت
Perhaps that's why Keita grew fond of his kindergarten teacher
لذا أصبح كيتا متعلّقاً بمعلّمته في الحضانة
and the women in the neighborhood.
ونساء الحيّ غالباً
I see. Now I get it.
فهمت، توضّح الأمر الآن
The kidnapper is likely working with a woman good with children,
يعمل الخاطف مع امرأة تجيد التعامل مع الأطفال غالباً
and she's taking care of Keita-kun.
وهي من يعتني بكيتا-كن
The old man might be right.
قد يكون العمّ مُحقاً
Meaning we can't rest easy, but it's unlikely they'll hurt Keita-kun.
،ما يعني لا يمكننا الاسترخاء لكن ليس من المُحتمل أنّهم سيؤذون كيتا-كن
Endo-san. I think you probably should call the police now...
...إيندو-سان، يُفترض عادةً أن نتّصل بالشرطة
I can't do that!
!لا يمكنني ذلك
Maybe the kidnappers will be caught if the police intervene!
ربما سيُقبض على الخاطف إذا تدّخلت الشرطة
But what guarantee do I have Keita will return unharmed?!
!لكن ما ضمان أن يرجع كيتا سالماً؟
Yes, but...
...مع ذلك
Mori-san!
!موري-سان
Yes?
أجل؟
You are my only hope now!
!أنت الوحيد الذي يمكنني الاعتماد عليه الآن
Please! Help bring Keita back unharmed!
!أرجوك! ساعدني بإعادة كيتا سالماً
I beg you!
أتوسّل إليك
Very well! I was the one who came to you!
فهمت! أنا من أتى بنفسه
Let's work together to somehow solve this!
لنعمل معاً لإيجاد حلّ للأمر
Thank you!
!شكراً جزيلاً
But we can't stay here too long.
لكن لا يمكننا البقاء هناء طويلاً
We'll leave for tonight and talk on the phone from now on.
سنغادر لهذه الليلة، ونتواصل على الهاتف بعدها
Right!
!حسناً
I'll need to borrow this photo.
أحتاج استعارة هذه الصورة
Yes, go right ahead.
حسناً، تفضّل
You have nothing to worry about. I will return Keita-kun safely!
لا حاجة للقلق، سأعيد كيتا-كن سالماً بكلّ تأكيد
Right! I appreciate your help!
!أجل! أقدّر مساعدتك
I attached the transmitter.
ألصقتُ جهاز الإرسال
Now we just wait for the kidnappers to call!
ما تبقّى هو انتظار اتّصال الخاطف فقط
Mori Detective Agency...
وكالة موري للتحرّي
They called?!
!اتّصل بك؟
What did they say?!
ماذا قال؟
They demanded 20 million more, and gave me two hours to get it!
طلب 20 مليوناً إضافية، ومنحني ساعتين فحسب لتجهيزها
Two hours?
ساعتين؟
Did you hear Keita-kun's voice?
أسمعت صوت كيتا-كن؟
Yes. I had them put him on just like you said.
أجل، طلبتُ أن يعطيه الهاتف كما قلتَ لي
Then he said something odd...
...ثمّ قال كيتا أمراً غريباً
Something odd?
أمراً غريباً؟
Keita! Is that you?!
!كيتا؟ أهذا أنت يا كيتا؟
Daddy!
!أبي
Keita! Are you okay?!
كيتا! أأنت بخير؟
Yeah! There's lots of crabs here, Daddy!
!أجل! يوجد الكثير من السرطانات هنا يا أبي
Crabs?
سرطانات؟
What're you talking about?
ما الذي تتكلم عنه؟
Listen! Call the cops and--
...اسمع! كما أخبرتُك بالأمس، إذا اتّصلت بالشرطة
A whale! A whale is spouting bubbles!
!حوت! حوت ينفث ماءً
Loudmouthed brat! I'll contact you again!
!يكفي ثرثرة! سأتّصل بك لاحقاً
Keita!
!كـ-كيتا
Hello?! Hello?!
!مرحباً؟ مرحباً؟
Loudmouthed? The kidnapper said that?
يكفي ثرثرة؟ هذا ما قاله الخاطف؟
Yes.
أجل
Understood. You get the money ready.
حسناً، جهّز المال يا إيندو-سان
With any luck, I'll have Keita-kun back within two hours!
إن مضت الأمور على ما يرام، سأُرجع كيتا-كن في غضون ساعتين
Really?! Please do your best!
!حـ-حقاً؟! ابذل ما بوسعك رجاءً
Dad! You have a clue about the kidnappers?!
أبي! لديك فكرة عن الخاطف؟
Yeah! Keita-kun is by lots of crabs and a bubble-spouting whale!
أجل، كيتا-كن في مكان به الكثير !من السرطانات، وحوت ينفث ماءً
Crabs and a whale?
سرطانات وحوت؟
Don't tell me it's the ocean...
لا تقصد البحر يا عمّ، صحيح؟
Don't be dumb! Whales only spout air deep underwater!
أحمق! عليك الإبحار لمكان مثل جزيرة أوغاساوارا !لرؤية نفث الحيتان للماء
It wasn't a real whale that Keita-kun saw. It was probably a model.
لم يكن ما رآه كيتا-كن حوتاً حقيقياً على الأرجح، بل نموذج
A model?
نموذج؟
And that would be at the aquarium!
!وذلك في المربى المائي
Southern Aquarium
المربى المائي الجنوبي
You don't have any whale models?
لا نماذج لحيتان لديكم؟
No. We do have various kinds of crabs, but no whale models...
،كلا، لدينا أنواع كثيرة من السرطانات ...لكن لا نماذج حيتان
Damn! Must be a different aquarium!
!تبّاً! لا بدّ أنّه مربى مائيّ آخر
We have no time! Let's go!
!لا وقت لدينا! لنسرع
Say... Are you sure the crabs have to be real?
اسمع يا عمّ، أأنت متأكد أن السرطانات حقيقية؟
What?
ماذا؟
When Keita-kun said there were lots of crabs,
عندما قال كيتا-كن أنّه توجد سرطانات كثيرة
the kidnapper said, "What are you talking about?"
"ردّ الخاطف "ما الذي تتكلم عنه؟
Doesn't that mean the kidnapper couldn't see any?
ألا يعني ذلك أنّه لم تكن هناك أيّ سرطانات بنظر الخاطف على الأقل؟
That is true...
...معك حق
So they didn't call from the aquarium?
لم يتّصل من المربى المائيّ إذاً ربما؟
Look at that, Dad! It's a whale!
!انظر هناك يا أبي! إنّه حوت
Nichiuri TV
أحتاجك تلفاز نيتشيوري
Oh, yeah! Nichiuri TV's mascot is a whale this year!
صحيح! شخصية حملة تلفاز نيتشيوري !الدعائية لهذا العام هي حوت
Could that be what Keita-kun saw?!
أيمكن أن يكون هذا الحوت الذي رآه كيتا-كن؟
If so, then he was where that blimp was visible...
في تلك الحالة، كان في مكان استطاع رؤية ذاك المنطاد منه
Got it! The blimp was above Beika Park when the kidnappers called!
عرفت! كان المنطاد فوق حديقة بيكا في الوقت الذي اتّصل فيه الخاطف
Beika Park?
حديقة بيكا؟
Yesterday's deal was at a hotel on Beika Street!
عمّ! مكان صفقة الأمس كان فندقاً !في جادة بيكا أيضاً
Let's go back and look for a place with lots of crabs!
لنرجع هناك ونبحث عن مكان يحوي الكثير من السرطانات
Keita-kun has to be somewhere near there!
!سنجد كيتا-كن بالقرب هناك حتماً
Any luck?!
كيف الأمر؟
Nope.
لم أجده
Me neither.
ولا أنا
Damn! Our time's up! The kidnappers might've called.
تبّاً! الوقت نفد تقريباً! ربما اتّصل الخاطف
Understood!
!فهمت
They called two minutes ago.
اتّصل قبل دقيقتين
They told him to stand at the end of Platform 1 in Karajuku Station.
أخبره بالوقوف في نهاية الرصيف الأوّل في محطّة كاراجوكو
Karajuku Station?
محطّة كاراجوكو؟
Yeah. You keep looking for the crabs, Conan.
أجل، واصل البحث عن السرطانات يا كونان
Got that?
فهمت؟
Yeah!
!أجل
Even if they did lose to the kidnappers, my transmitter's on the case!
حتّى لو فقدوا أثر الخاطف، جهاز إرسالي على الحقيبة
I will find them!
!سأجد مكانه بالتأكيد
Karajuku Station
محطّة كاراجوكو
Do you think they'll be on a train?
أتظنّ الخاطف سيخبره بصعود القطار؟
I doubt it.
ذلك محتمل
They'll probably exchange the money elsewhere.
سيتمّان صفقة التبادل في مكان مختلف غالباً
Hey!
!أنت
Throw the money here!
!ارم الحقيبة هنا
Don't you care about the kid?!
!لا تهتمّ بما سيحلّ بصبيّك؟
Darn it! Ran!
!تبّاً... ران
Right!
!أجل
He got away?!
!هرب؟
Yes. But Mori-san got the license plate number on film.
أجل، لكن حصل موري-سان على صورة لأرقام لوحة درّاجته
We'll know his identity soon!
!سنعرف هويّته قريباً
Got it!
!حسناً
It's staying in the same spot. Their hideout should be nearby!
!إنّها ساكنة في نفس المكان، يُفترض أنّ المخبأ بالقرب
Almost there! Just around that corner!
!أكاد أصل! عند ذاك المنعطف
Darn it! They must've changed briefcases here!
!تبّاً! لا بدّ أنّه بدّل الحقيبة هنا
But the old man got the license plate number, so we can still--
...لكنّ العم صوّر رقم لوحة الدرّاجة، لذا لن يستطيع الخاطف
Was this the kidnapper's?! Was that license plate a fake?!
!أهذه للخاطف؟! أيمكن أنّ اللوحة كانت مزيّفة؟
Oh no! Now that they have the money, they might kill Keita-kun!
،كلا! بعدما أصبح المال بيده الآن !قد يُقدم على قتل كيتا-كن إذا لم ألحق به
Darn it!
!تبّاً
Find it!
!عليّ إيجاده
Find where there's lots of crabs and where the whale blimp was visible!
مكان به الكثير من السرطانات ويمكنك !رؤية منطاد الحوت منه
Didn't he say the whale was spouting air bubbles?
ألم يقل كيتا-كن أنّ الحوت كان ينفث ماءً؟
That blimp wasn't spouting anything!
!لم يكن ذاك المنطاد ينفث شيئاً
What does it mean? Was it not the blimp he saw?! Or maybe--
ما الذي يعنيه هذا؟ لم يكن ما رآه ...كيتا-كن المنطاد؟ أو ربما
Could it be?!
...أيمكن
Can't see it from here.
لا يمكنني رؤيته من هنا
It might be visible from that Starlight Hotel!
!ربما يمكن رؤيته من فندق ستارلايت
Beika Park. And then that.
حديقة بيكا... بعدها ذاك
Keita-kun saw the smoke from that waste incineration facility...
ما رآه كيتا-كن هو الدخان من مصنع ...حرق النفايات ذاك
It would look like that only where the park and the tower line up...
لا يمكن رؤية ذلك إلّا عندما تقع كلّ من الحديقة ومصنع حرق النّفايات على نفس خطّ البصر
That's right around here!
!هنا تماماً
But this is too low. It needs to be the same altitude as the blimp
...لكنّ الارتفاع منخفض، يجب أن يكون عالياً بمستوى المنطاد
to make it look like it's spouting air.
بحيث يبدو أنّ الحوت ينفث ماءً
Could they be in this hotel?!
!أيمكن أنّهما في هذا الفندق؟
That was close!
كان ذلك خطراً
The tables and chairs...
...الطاولة والكراسي
Could the crabs actually be--
...أيمكن أنّ السرطانات
There they are! The crabs!
!ها هي! السرطانات
The tables and chairs look like crabs from above!
!تبدو الطاولات والكراسي كسرطانات من الأعلى
No doubt about it! Keita-kun is in some room in this hotel!
لا شكّ في الأمر! كيتا-كن في غرفة ما !في هذا الفندق
Lady!
!يا عمّة
Do you know which room this boy is staying in?
أتعرفين في أيّ غرفة يقيم هذا الفتى؟
Oh, he's in a room one floor down. But he just left with his parents.
،إنّه في غرفة في الطابق أسفل هذا لكنّه غادر قبل قليل مع والديه
Thank you!
!شكراً لك
Alright! I found you! Keita-kun is still unharmed!
!حسناً، وجدتك! لا يزال كيتا-كن سليماً
Yaiba Punch!
!لكمة يايبا
Let's go, Joker! Hiyaaah!
!هيّا بنا يا جوكر
Hey, are we really going to kill him?
أخبرني، هل سنقتله حقّاً؟
Quit asking and stop worrying about him!
!يكفي! لا تشفقي عليه
Let's go!
هيّا بنا
Keita-kun!
!كيتا-كن
Those two are kidnappers! Stop them!
!هذان الاثنان خاطفان! أوقفوهما
Damn! Nobody move!
!تبّاً! لا يتحرّك أحد
Move and he's dead!
!سيفقد حياته إذا تحرّكتم
Get over there! Now!
!ابتعدا! بسرعة
Is there anything to kick?!
أهناك ما يمكنني ركله؟
The bike's right out front! Run like hell once we're out the door!
!ركنت الدراجة في الخارج مباشرةً اركضي بأقصى سرعة حالما نغادر من الباب
Ready?
مستعدة؟
Take this!
!خُذا
And that's that!
!حُلّت بسلام
Keita! I'm so glad you're all right! Keita!
!كيتا! حمداً لله على سلامتك! كيتا
Daddy, that hurts!
أبي، هذا مؤلم
How did you know they were here?
كيف عرفت أنّهم هنا؟
It was just dumb luck!
!بالصدفة
I was looking for the crabs when I found Keita-kun!
!كنتُ أبحث عن السرطانات ووجدتُ كيتا-كن
When I shouted that it was a kidnapping, they rushed to get away
عندما صرختُ أنّهما مُختطفان، حاول المجرمان الهرب
and wound up like that.
وانتهى بهما الأمر هكذا
Brought it upon themselves, huh?
جنيا على نفسيهما إذاً؟
Mori-kun!
!موري-كن
Oh, Inspector Megure-dono!
!سيّدي المفتّش ميغوري
Conan-kun explained everything.
أخبرني كونان-كن بكلّ شيء
Why didn't you contact us when you learned it was a kidnapping?
لمَ لم تتّصل بنا بعدما عرفت أنّه اختطاف؟
Can't trust me, huh?
لم تستطع الثقة بي؟
It's not that at all!
!كلا! لم يكن شيئاً كذاك البتّة
For the next hour, Inspector Megure gave the old man a good scolding.
تلقّى العمّ بعدها توبيخاً مستمراً لساعة من المفتّش ميغوري
Not that that's a bad thing!
لا بأس بذلك من حين لآخر
What was that?
ما كان ذلك؟
This is a homicide!
!إنّها جريمة قتل
It wouldn't be possible to leave from here.
يستحيل أن يخرج أحد من هنا
Why is there a bloodstain here?
لمَ توجد بقعة دم هنا؟
Ikuta-san was standing here in the dark.
كان إيكوتا-سان يقف هنا في الظلام
Could it be?!
...أيمكن
The Pitch Dark Road Murder Case
جريمة قتل الطريق المُظلم
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Tobacco.
سجائر
Next episode features yet another shocking and impressive trick.
تتضمّن الحلقة القادمة !حيلة ماكرة مفاجئة
Can you see the crows in the dark?
أيمكنك رؤية غراب الظلام؟